No 5 Sam-Urewuji Avenue Owerri ImoState, Nigeria. +234-903-907-5524, chibuezeodii@gmail.com



Odii Marshall Chibueze

I am an experienced software developer over two years of experience in programming and offering IT solutions to the society. I am grossly involved in developing mobile apps that run on android, iOS and windows phones with Flutter. Aside software development I'm a good web content developer, I write articles for websites, blogs etc and publish them online with effective SEO skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer
February 2021 – November 2021
NEBULA HEIGHTS INCOPORATION

Project: An artiifical Intelligent app that transcribes audio to text

- ◆ Use Flutter technology to develop apps
- **♦** Consume Payment gateway APIs
- **♦** Consume Third party APIs
- Perform 2FA on Mobile app
- Transform Adobe XD/Figma UI to codes
- Maintain good User Experience

No 5 Sam-Urewuji Avenue Owerri ImoState, Nigeria. +234-903-907-5524, chibuezeodii@gmail.com

- Maintain best coding practices
- ◆ Use efficient architectural and design patterns, MVP, MVVM, BLoC
- ♦ Deploy Apps to Google Play Store
- Deploy Apps to Apple Store
- Deploy applications to Dedicated Servers
- Test app on different mobile devices
- Good experience in debugging.
- Utilize local storage on mobile using SQLFLITE or SQLITE
- Used AES, TRIPLEDES encryption algorithms to secure data
- Strictly maintain Agile/Scrum rules and methodologies
- Experience on multi-threading, data structures, algorithms, object-oriented design, and design patterns
- Created RESTful APIs using firebase cloud functions

Software Engineer (Remote)

December 2020 - March 2021

FIXBOT TECHNOLOGIES (A startup company)

Projects: Mobile Application for a Car diagnostics App

Mobile and Web Application for Ecommerce of Car Spare parts and Repairs

- Setup and configured Android Studio environment for flutter development
- ◆ Worked closed with the business to gather business requirements
- Used Dart to develop business rules that drives the integration of the app to the back end system
- Good experience with Dart for Android and JavaScript for Web App
- Deployed Apps to Google Play Store
- Experience with designing and developing client-side graphical user interfaces using NodeJS and a React framework called GatsbyJS
- Deployed Web App to a VPS
- Participated in AGILE SCRUM meetings.
- Strictly maintain Agile/Scrum rules and methodologies
- Experience on multi-threading, data structures, algorithms, object-oriented design, and design patterns
- ◆ Build and led testing of the app on different mobile devices
- Good experience in debugging

Developer (Full-time Remote)

No 5 Sam-Urewuji Avenue Owerri ImoState, Nigeria. +234-903-907-5524, chibuezeodii@gmail.com

September 2020 - November 2020

MATICAU LTD

Projects: Staff Attendance Management System

- Developed mobile application to capture staff with Flutter/Dart Technology
- ◆ Used Google geolocation services to pick staff location on attendance.
- **♦** Implemented the use of tokenization in API calls
- Utilized frameworks such as Hibernate and Spring for persistence and application layers
- **♦** Participated in AGILE SCRUM meetings.
- Used a hybridized method for development. AGILE/Waterfall
- This Project also Included Authentication, Security, Emails and Phone Capabilities to ensure the Intruder is detected and prevented.
- **♦** Experience on data structures, algorithms, object-oriented design, and design patterns

Software Engineer (Freelance, Remote)

March 2020 – December 2020

BUNCH BAY NIG LTD (A tech startup company)

Projects: Mobile Application for a Doctor Service App
Mobile Application for a Ecommerce App
Mobile and Web Application for a Biller Service Payment System

- Experience with designing and developing client-side graphical user interfaces using nodejs and a React framework called Gatsby and CRA
- Deployed Web App to a VPS
- Participated in AGILE SCRUM meetings.
- Deploy web applications to Dedicated Servers
- Test app on different mobile devices
- Utilize local storage on mobile using SQLFLITE or SQLITE
- ◆ Used AES, TRIPLEDES encryption algorithms to secure data
- Strictly maintain Agile/Scrum rules and methodologies
- Experience on multi-threading, data structures, algorithms, object-oriented design, and design patterns
- **♦** Consume Payment gateway APIs
- Consume Third party APIs
- Build and led testing of the app on different mobile devices
- Good experience in debugging

No 5 Sam-Urewuji Avenue Owerri ImoState, Nigeria. +234-903-907-5524, chibuezeodii@gmail.com

Developer (Remote)

December 2018 - February 2019

SOLUTION APP STUDIO

Projects: USSD Call App used access mobile banking services and mobile network services

- Setup and configured Android Studio environment
- Worked closed with the business to gather business requirements
- Used Java to develop business rules that drives the integration of the app to the back end system
- Good experience with Java for Android and JavaScript
- ◆ Deployed Apps to Google Play Store
- Build and led testing of the app on different mobile devices
- Good experience in debugging.

Web Content Developer (Freelance)

December 2015 - September 2018

SPORTSMANGIST.COM ISCHOLARSHIPGRANTS.COM

MOBILETECHTIPS.COM

- Engaged in writing articles and publishing the articles on the websites with good SEO skills and knowledge
- ◆ Made use of WordPress and Couch CMS to organize the websites
- ◆ Effectively advertise the website on the social media and through google ads
- On daily basis, update the contents on the websites.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE PROFICIENCES AND SKILLS

- Hypertext Markup Language (HTML).
- Cascading Style Sheet (CSS)
- JavaScript
- Dart
- Flutter
- TypeScript on Ionic Framework
- Structured Query Language (SQL)
- CMS like WordPress and Couch
- ❖ Agile Methodology
- Scrum Technique
- **❖** Java
- Github/Gitlab

No 5 Sam-Urewuji Avenue Owerri ImoState, Nigeria. +234-903-907-5524, chibuezeodii@gmail.com

Solidity and Web3

CERTIFICATES OBTAINED WITH DATES

\$	Sololearn Certified HTML Developer	2019
\$	Sololearn Certified CSS Developer	2019
\$	Sololearn Certified JavaScript Developer	2019
\$	Udemy Certified iPhone and Android App Developer	2020
\$	Sololearn Certified C++ Developer	2020
\$	Sololearn Certified Java Developer	2020
\$	CodeSpace Technology Certified Android App Developer	2020
\$	Udemy Certified Android App Developer	2021

EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS ATTENDED WITH DATES

•	Federal University of Technology Owerri, Imo State	(2019-till date)
\$	Logos International Secondary School Owerri	(2012- 2019)
\$	University Staff School, Federal University of Technology Owerri	(2002 -2012)

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION WITH DATES

•	SSCE (O/Level), Logos International Secondary School, Imo State	(2015-2019)
\$	Junior WAEC, Logos International Secondary School, Imo State	(2012 - 2015)

First School Leaving Certificate, University Staff School, Federal University of Technology Owerri (2002 -2009)

CONFERENCES AND WORKSHOPS ATTENDED

- ➤ The 10th Annual Conference of NACOSS SouthEast Zonal Conference, on Evolution Processes in Information and Communication Technology, held at Akanu Ibiam Federal Polytechnic Unwana, Ebonyi State on January 2018.
- ➤ A National Software Summit of the Nigeria Association of Computer Science Students (NACOSS), on Contemporary Software Developers, Their Tools and Techniques, held at University of Nigeria Nsukka, Enugu State from 19th 22nd June **2018**.

No 5 Sam-Urewuji Avenue Owerri ImoState, Nigeria. +234-903-907-5524, chibuezeodii@gmail.com

> The NACOSS National Conference, on Information Technology the Framework for

National Advancement, held at Ladoke Akintola University of Technology Ogbomoso, Oyo State on the 17^{th} – 19^{th} of October **2018**

ADMINISTRATIVE EXPERIENCE

- ➤ 2012 to 2013----- Class Prefect, Logos International Secondary School (LOGISS)
- 2018/2019 ----- President, JETS Club (LOGISS)
- ➤ 2018/2019 ----- Lead Ambassador, Microsoft Student Learn Ambassador, MLSA FUTO
- ➤ 2019/2020 ----- **Co-lead,** Developer Student Club, DSC FUTO
- > 2021 till date ----- Chairman, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, IEEE FUTO Student branch

ACTIVE MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL BODIES

- Member----- Microsoft Student Learn Ambassador, (MLSA FUTO)
- ➤ Member----- Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers (IEEE)
- ➤ Member ----- Nigeria Association of Computer Science Students (NACOSS)
- ➤ Member -----Google Developer Group FUTO (GDG-FUTO)
- Member ------FUTO Tech Community (FTC)

COMMUNITY SERVICE

- ❖ Member, Uburu Peoples Assembly Owerri Branch
- ❖ Member, Umu-Njoku Family Union 1998 Date
- ❖ Member Watchman Catholic Renewal Movement Youth Organization.
- Member, Okposi Development Union
- ❖ Member, IEEE Council of Chairmen
- Organizer, IEEE Symposium

RECREATIONAL ACTIVITIES

No 5 Sam-Urewuji Avenue Owerri ImoState, Nigeria. +234-903-907-5524, chibuezeodii@gmail.com

- Running
- Programming
- Football
- Travelling
- Skill Acquisition

REFEREES

- Engr. O. J. Eze, CEO OjPeters Inc, Senior Business Systems Consultant Canada Brampton Canada, Email: ojpeters@gmail.com
- 2. **Engr. Alphonsus Eze**, Cyber Security Analyst, Scotiabank, Ontario Canada, Email: alphonsus eze@yahoo.com
- 3. **Dr. Mrs. J. N Odii,** Department of Computer Science, School of Physical Sciences, Federal University of Technology Owerri. Email: jnodii@yahoo.com, +2348035373137
- 4. **Mrs. F. Nwokoma**, Department Computer Science, Federal University of Technology Owerri Imo State. Email <u>adibefrancisca@yahoo.com</u>, +2348060011112